<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Gessert Books</title>
    <description>Book design, typesetting, and typography in Amarillo, Texas.
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 21:26:26 -0600</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 31 Dec 2016 21:26:26 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.3.0</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Eisenstein's Monster</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This book was a real treat to lay out, because it included such a wide variety of prose styles. Nearly every chapter required a different sort of presentation, all coming together like patchwork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/eisensteins-monster/em-cover.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;The Book Cover&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;The cover is meant to reflect the convergence aspect of the book. The radial pattern is made up of many smaller symbols that have meaning in the story.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/eisensteins-monster/em-title.png&quot; alt=&quot;The title page&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;The title page.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/eisensteins-monster/em-section-opener.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Title Page&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Section openers.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/eisensteins-monster/em-chapter-opener-strikethrough.png&quot; alt=&quot;The Title Page&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Chapter openers and strikethrough text.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/eisensteins-monster/em-japanese.png&quot; alt=&quot;p 268&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;One of the chapters in the book required Japanese text.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/eisensteins-monster/em-nested-blockquote.png&quot; alt=&quot;p 293&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;And another used nested blockquotes for style.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/eisensteins-monster/em-footnotes.png&quot; alt=&quot;pp 342-343&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Footnotes exist in many chapters, and some are very structured and complex.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/eisensteins-monster/em-log.png&quot; alt=&quot;pp 388-389&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;A late chapter is formatted like a log or journal, and I made a number of adjustments to reflect that style.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/eisensteins-monster/em-font.png&quot; alt=&quot;p 407&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;For the same chapter, we had a need for inline geometric shapes, so I created a custom symbol font for that purpose.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/eisensteins-monster/em-table.png&quot; alt=&quot;p 416&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;And it included a few tables, and other elements that are more common for non-fiction than fiction.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/eisensteins-monster/em-dialogue.png&quot; alt=&quot;p 484-485&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Toward the end of the book, a number of shorter pieces are assembled, and they've got a variety of formatting styles as well. This is an extended dialogue. &lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/eisensteins-monster/em-script.png&quot; alt=&quot;p 494-495&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;And here we've got a transition into something like a script format.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/eisensteins-monster/em-comic.png&quot; alt=&quot;p 502-503 or 510-511&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;This is a text-only interpretation of the pages of a comic book. It also includes nested footnotes.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/eisensteins-monster/em-strikethrough.png&quot; alt=&quot;p 549&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;More heavy use of strike-through.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed finding creative and mostly semantic ways to create all of these different styles, while trying to make design decisions that can work for ebook as well wherever possible:&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/eisensteins-monster/em-ios.png&quot; alt=&quot;p 549&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/eisensteins-monster/em-osx.png&quot; alt=&quot;p 549&quot; /&gt;
	
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Eisenstein’s Monster&lt;/em&gt; is available on Amazon in print and ebook.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 12 Nov 2016 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/11/12/eisensteins-monster.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/11/12/eisensteins-monster.html</guid>
        
        <category>font design</category>
        
        <category>print layout</category>
        
        <category>ebook formatting</category>
        
        <category>cover design</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Black Terrorist</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve completed a full book design for an English edition of The Black Terrorist, a historical novel about the French Resistance and colonial contribution to it. After escaping from German forces in World War II, Addi Ba  encounters members of the French Resistance and leads a Resistance network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/black-terrorist/bt-cover.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;The cover photo features the real Addi Ba , ca. 1940.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/black-terrorist/bt-jacket.png&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;The book jacket.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/black-terrorist/bt-pages.png&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Page layout for the print edition. Our aim was to keep it simple and elegant.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a fun layout, because it lacked any sort of chapter head, so each unnamed chapter simply starts on the next page, marked with whitespace. We used a simple section break marker for subchapters. Here’s the book on my 5th gen…&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/black-terrorist/bt-kindle-1.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/black-terrorist/bt-kindle-2.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/black-terrorist/bt-ibooks-osx.png&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;...and here's a spread view in iBooks (OSX).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/black-terrorist/bt-kindle-osx.png&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Here's a look at the ebook in the Kindle desktop app...&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/black-terrorist/bt-ibooks-ios.jpg&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;...and here it is in iBooks for iOS.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Diasporic Africa Press is a nonprofit publisher focusing on works that describe African cultural impact. I’ve worked with them for a number of years now, and it’s always a treat–because the books they feature are always fascinating. A couple years ago, I built a consistent branding and style direction for all the non-fiction works they publish, and we’ve been using it for those works ever since:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/black-terrorist/dap-array.png&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2016 12:00:00 -0600</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2016/01/18/the-black-terrorist.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2016/01/18/the-black-terrorist.html</guid>
        
        <category>print layout</category>
        
        <category>ebook formatting</category>
        
        <category>cover design</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Botanical Frankenstein</title>
        <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In Eastern lands they talk in flow’rs&lt;br /&gt;
And they tell in a garland their loves and cares;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Each blossom that blooms in their garden bowr’s,&lt;br /&gt;
 On its leaves a mystic language bears.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The rose is a sign of joy and love,&lt;br /&gt;
 Young blushing love in its earliest dawn,&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And the mildness that suits the gentle dove,&lt;br /&gt;
 From the myrtle’s snowy flow’rs is drawn.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Innocence gleams in the lily’s bell,&lt;br /&gt;
 Pure as the heart in its native heaven.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Fame’s bright star and glory’s swell&lt;br /&gt;
 By the glossy leaf of the bay are given.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The silent, soft and humble heart,&lt;br /&gt;
 In the violet’s hidden sweetness breathes,&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And the tender soul that cannot part,&lt;br /&gt;
 In a twine of evergreen fondly wreathes.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The cypress that daily shades the grave,&lt;br /&gt;
 Is sorrow that moans her bitter lot,&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And faith that a thousand ills can brave,&lt;br /&gt;
 Speaks in thy blue leaves “forget-me-not”.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Then gather a wreath from the garden bowers,&lt;br /&gt;
 And tell the wish of thy heart in flowers.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;James Gates Percival&lt;br /&gt;
 The Language of Flowers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really love examining books. I’m not an English scholar or anything
like that, but I do enjoy figuring the different themes and ideas in a
novel, and trying my best to appreciate them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And when you design a book, particularly the page layout, it’s really
easy to get next to the work itself, and feel close to it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This year, on Mary Shelley’s birthday, I decided to read her
&lt;em&gt;Frankenstein&lt;/em&gt; for the first time. And a second, and a third, and to get
as near to it as I could by working an interesting design for it. I
hoped other folks might enjoy reading it for the first time, like I did,
and especially so close to Halloween.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/botanical-frankenstein/cover.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;The Book Cover.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I began by reading the excellent Norton Critical Edition of
&lt;em&gt;Frankenstein&lt;/em&gt;, along with all the great essays included in that volume.
I remember as I read, I would happen on some thought or other about the
book, and would then be weirdly disappointed when it would be even
partly validated by one of the essays, as though I was the first person
to ever have some specific thought about this 200 year old book. I had a
good laugh when I realized how goofy that was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love context, so I read up on Mary Shelley’s life, listened to some
music of the era and tried to educate myself a bit about Romanticism.
This was an awesome part of the project for me, absorbing lots of great
art and doing my best to see things the way they might’ve seen them. The
world is so different now, I’m not sure how possible that really is. But
I remember walking through the park and turning away from traffic,
finding a small patch of some grass or other, and imagining that folks
in Shelley’s era might see a tiny patch of grass just like that, and it
wasn’t actually all that long ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Around this time, I started to imagine that the Creature in the book
wasn’t ugly at all. I got really wrapped up in the idea that the
Creature was actually beautiful, like an angel, and that the only reason
people react poorly to him has something to do with his &lt;em&gt;manner&lt;/em&gt;, not
his look. Like we can subconsciously identify when life came from
something divine—and when that’s not where a life came from, we don’t
want it anywhere near us. Or like we don’t know what’s wrong here, we
can’t put our finger on it, but we know we don’t like it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And I got all excited thinking this was right, because after all, the
Creature was made to be perfect. The doctor was working with him all
this time, wouldn’t he have known he was ugly before he came to life?
And then he comes to life, and nothing different except he’s alive now,
but suddenly he’s grotesque and awful? So surely this means it’s
something about the &lt;em&gt;life&lt;/em&gt; that’s wrong.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This interpretation was plainly wrong though, based on the elder
DeLacey’s reaction to him; and when I realized it, I ditched that
thought. But I loved just having that thought and examining it, all the
way up to discarding it completely. I ditched other ideas too, like the
idea that the Creature and the Doctor are the same person, stuff like
that. I still wonder if the Creature is lying about the DeLacey’s
backstory though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I watched a ton of Frankenstein movies around this time too, even though
they rarely relate to the book all that much. I just wanted to surround
myself with the whole idea as best I could. I remember when the Branagh
version first came out, I loved it—and I was really excited to see it
again. But having read the book, it really didn’t suit me near as much,
and I especially didn’t like the way the movie adjusted Elizabeth’s
story at the end.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I did see &lt;em&gt;Frankenstein: The True Story&lt;/em&gt; for the first time though, and
I think this was my favorite of the ones I saw. Which is funny because
it strays from the book much, much more; but in this case it feels like
interpretation. Would definitely recommend it to anyone looking for a
cool take on the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/botanical-frankenstein/title.gif&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;The Title Page.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I went through two general design concepts before landing on the right
one. First, I wanted to take general subjects from each chapter and
basically just represent them in a direct way within the dropcaps. For
example, in the chapter where the Doctor is reading a lot of occult
materials, I’d have used a pentagram or similar for the cap. But this
wasn’t exactly a super fun way to go about it, and honestly it wasn’t
enough of a constraint on the design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I imagined the Creature sort of like a bouquet. Assembled from all
sorts of different flowers in order to be beautiful. I started
researching flower symbolism and completed a full set of caps linking a
flower to a theme within each chapter. This was a cool idea too, because
it’s not distracting at all to the reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I liked the link to nature, especially in the context of Romanticism,
and the more grim aspects of the story rub against lush plants really
well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This was a funny thing though, because there is an absurdly huge amount
of flower symbols out there, differing by culture. It started to feel
like I could pretty much find a flower to represent almost anything I
wanted, and that sorta killed that idea dead. Because it wouldn’t really
mean much.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Then I happened on a poem by James Gates Percival.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In Eastern lands they talk in flow’rs&lt;br /&gt;
 And they tell in a garland their loves and cares;&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Each blossom that blooms in their garden bowr’s,&lt;br /&gt;
 On its leaves a mystic language bears.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The rose is a sign of joy and love,&lt;br /&gt;
 Young blushing love in its earliest dawn,&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And the mildness that suits the gentle dove,&lt;br /&gt;
 From the myrtle’s snowy flow’rs is drawn.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Innocence gleams in the lily’s bell,&lt;br /&gt;
 Pure as the heart in its native heaven.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Fame’s bright star and glory’s swell&lt;br /&gt;
 By the glossy leaf of the bay are given.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The silent, soft and humble heart,&lt;br /&gt;
 In the violet’s hidden sweetness breathes,&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And the tender soul that cannot part,&lt;br /&gt;
 In a twine of evergreen fondly wreathes.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;The cypress that daily shades the grave,&lt;br /&gt;
 Is sorrow that moans her bitter lot,&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;And faith that a thousand ills can brave,&lt;br /&gt;
 Speaks in thy blue leaves “forget-me-not”.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Then gather a wreath from the garden bowers,&lt;br /&gt;
 And tell the wish of thy heart in flowers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was really struck by this because so many of the flowers and plants he
describes suit the book perfectly. I really had no need for any flowers
besides the ones he listed here, and I could use them to represent
characters or relationships within the book. This poem became the seed
for the entire design, and I’ve used it to further frame the work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-flowers&quot;&gt;The Flowers&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;small-img&quot; src=&quot;/img/portfolio/botanical-frankenstein/rose.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;The rose is a sign of joy and love,&lt;br /&gt;  
 		Young blushing love in its earliest dawn,&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used the rose to represent non-romantic love, specifically close
childhood friendship, and I placed this flower wherever Clerval figured
heavily.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;small-img&quot; src=&quot;/img/portfolio/botanical-frankenstein/myrtle.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;And the mildness that suits the gentle dove,&lt;br /&gt;
 From the myrtle’s snowy flow’rs is drawn.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used the myrtle to represent the DeLaceys at their cottage, because
their life felt so idyllic.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;small-img&quot; src=&quot;/img/portfolio/botanical-frankenstein/lily.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Innocence gleams in the lily’s bell,&lt;br /&gt;  
 Pure as the heart in its native heaven.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used the lily to tie different threads in Justine’s story together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;small-img&quot; src=&quot;/img/portfolio/botanical-frankenstein/bay.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Fame’s bright star and glory’s swell  &lt;br /&gt;
 By the glossy leaf of the bay are given.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used the bay leaf for early parts of the Doctor’s story. I also used
it for Walton.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;small-img&quot; src=&quot;/img/portfolio/botanical-frankenstein/violet.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;The silent, soft and humble heart,  &lt;br /&gt;
 In the violet’s hidden sweetness breathes,&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used the violet for the way the DeLacey’s backstory humbled them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;small-img&quot; src=&quot;/img/portfolio/botanical-frankenstein/pine.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;And the tender soul that cannot part,  &lt;br /&gt;
 In a twine of evergreen fondly wreathes.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used a pine cone for the Creature’s early story, to represent his
desire for connection.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;small-img&quot; src=&quot;/img/portfolio/botanical-frankenstein/cypress.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;The cypress that daily shades the grave,  &lt;br /&gt;
 Is sorrow that moans her bitter lot,&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But by the story’s end, I used the Cypress’ cone for both the Creature
and the Doctor.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img class=&quot;small-img&quot; src=&quot;/img/portfolio/botanical-frankenstein/f-m-n.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;And faith that a thousand ills can brave,  &lt;br /&gt;
 Speaks in thy blue leaves “forget-me-not”.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I used the Forget-Me-Not for romantic love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-caps&quot;&gt;The Caps&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/botanical-frankenstein/caps.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;I chose Georgia as the base, because it’s the nearest to
period-appropriate and is available on many devices without the need for
font embedding.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-pages&quot;&gt;The Pages&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/botanical-frankenstein/ibooks-osx.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;iBooks on OS X&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/botanical-frankenstein/kindle-osx.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Kindle on OS X&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/botanical-frankenstein/ibooks-ios.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;iBooks on iOS&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/botanical-frankenstein/kindle5.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Kindle e-ink&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really loved this book, and could easily go on and on about it. It’s
one of those works that you can rework in your mind to mean a million
different things, and I figure that’s why it’s a classic. The story
itself is great, but it also just gives your mind a fun sandbox to play
in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope that people will enjoy giving it a read. I’ll be re-reading it
myself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the curious, I’ve published my &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.evernote.com/pub/phillipgessert/botanicalfrankenstein&quot;&gt;Evernote
notebook&lt;/a&gt;
for the project. It’s got around 200 notes and web clippings I gathered
over the course of the project. It’s not remotely organized, but some
folks might find it fun to flip through.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you know anyone that might like to read Frankenstein for the first
time, please don’t hesitate to shoot them a link—or if you read it and
you want to talk to me about it, you can find me
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.twitter.com/phillipgessert&quot;&gt;@phillipgessert&lt;/a&gt; on Twitter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Awhile he grasps at Science, with the strong,&lt;br /&gt;
 Fierce spirit of ambition, when his car&lt;br /&gt;
 O’er fortune’s field of blood is borne along,&lt;br /&gt;
 Drawn by the wildly rushing steeds of war,&lt;br /&gt;
 And hurrying on in quest of Fame’s bright star,&lt;br /&gt;
 That shines through smoke and dust and wounds and gore;&lt;br /&gt;
 Justice and mercy cannot raise a bar&lt;br /&gt;
 Across the torrent of his wrath, its roar&lt;br /&gt;
 Drives virtue, love and peace affrighted from its shore.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;James Gates Percival&lt;br /&gt;
 From Prometheus, A Poem&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can download my edition of &lt;em&gt;Frankenstein&lt;/em&gt; for free: &lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/RORv8J&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;ePub&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;https://goo.gl/gFm37f&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;MOBI&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;For feedback or comments on this project, please use this &lt;a href=&quot;http://goo.gl/forms/6pgBqfcG9p&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot;&gt;feedback form&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 14 Oct 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2015/10/14/botanical-frankenstein.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/10/14/botanical-frankenstein.html</guid>
        
        <category>ebook formatting</category>
        
        <category>drop caps</category>
        
        <category>cover design</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>The Chimera Sequence</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I had a blast working on Elliott Garber’s new bio-thriller: The Chimera Sequence. We worked together to build hardcover, paperback and Kindle versions that offered the best experience for his readers, and reinforced the themes of the work without drawing too much attention to style. Elliott has a ton of design savvy and it was a real treat to work with him.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/chimera/chimera-cover.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;The ebook cover. Elliott's veterinary background was a great help in illustrating the gorilla, as he was able to point out details about the creature's proportions and anatomy that might've eluded me with photo references alone.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/chimera/chimera-pb.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;The paperback jacket.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/chimera/chimera-hc.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;The hardcover dust jacket.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/chimera/chimera-au.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Audiobook.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/chimera/interior-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;A few pages from the interior.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/chimera/interior-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Some from the front matter.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-the-book&quot;&gt;About the Book&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Chimera Sequence is available on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.amazon.com/dp/B00YB39DSM/?tag=kbpst-20&quot;&gt;Amazon&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2015 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2015/09/18/the-chimera-sequence.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2015/09/18/the-chimera-sequence.html</guid>
        
        <category>illustration</category>
        
        <category>print layout</category>
        
        <category>ebook formatting</category>
        
        <category>cover design</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Diasporic Africa Press</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Diasporic Africa Press is a nonprofit publisher focusing on works that describe African cultural impact. I’ve worked with the publisher for a while, and we recently worked together to build a fresh style to flow through the works—a style that suits the content while keeping each book’s style consistent but distinctive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/dap/cover-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;I used concentric rings as a visual analogy for diaspora.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/dap/cover-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;For this one, I pulled color inspiration from the Brazilian flag.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/dap/cover-3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;The project was featured in &lt;a href=&quot;https://dribbble.com/stories/2014/08/04/weekly-replay&quot;&gt;Dribbble's Weekly Replay for Aug 4, 2014.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/dap/interior-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;The text layout.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/dap/fonts.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many of the works include special characters, and I wanted to choose a typeface for body text that was flexible enough to handle this reliably while still carrying an appealing look. I chose &lt;a href=&quot;http://scripts.sil.org/gentium&quot;&gt;Gentium&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;…a typeface family designed to enable the diverse ethnic groups around the world who use the Latin, Cyrillic and Greek scripts to produce readable, high-quality publications. It supports a wide range of Latin- and Cyrillic-based alphabets.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I chose Seravek as a complement—it also has fairly strong support for special characters, and the pair looks great together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Phillip and I have worked together for a few years now and with each project he has devoted himself to the task and will not quit until the job is done to satisfaction. Very personable and detailed-oriented, I recommend him highly!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Kwasi Konadu&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/dap/jacket-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;The rings from the front cover wrap over the spine to the back cover, to give the volumes a distinctive look on the shelf.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/dap/jackets-array.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Color and image varies, but the overall design is consistent from volume-to-volume. This helps make each one easily identifiable as a publication of Diasporic Africa Press.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I always have a blast designing books for Diasporic Africa Press—largely because I always manage to learn something new as I work through them. To find out more about the publisher, including their aims and information on available books, check out &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dafricapress.com&quot;&gt;dafricapress.com&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2014/09/01/diasporic-africa-press.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2014/09/01/diasporic-africa-press.html</guid>
        
        <category>branding</category>
        
        <category>print layout</category>
        
        <category>ebook formatting</category>
        
        <category>cover design</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>No Shirt, No Shoes, No Service</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I had the opportunity to help design a memoir—Steve Cox’s &lt;em&gt;No Shirt, No Shoes, No Service&lt;/em&gt;. Steve talks a bit about his experience hitchhiking across the United States in the early 70s with a buddy of his. It was a really fun read, and a fun project, too.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/no-shirt/no-shirt-cover.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;The front cover for the story. Since the endpoint for the hitchhiking trip was the Colorado Rockies, I wanted to represent not just HITCHhiking, but HIKING as well. So I worked with the idea of a hitchhiker's hand doubling as a mountain, with our tiny hikers on top of it.&lt;/p&gt;
 		&lt;p&gt;To visualize this, I took a photo of my own hand and scribbled some figures onto it, you can see that photo as one of my work-in-progress shots &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.behance.net/wip/286879/537605&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;. There's an outline view of the finished illustration, too.&lt;/p&gt;
 		&lt;p&gt;I originally played with the placing a small waterfall at the base of the thumb, but this broke the feel of the cover a bit. It felt less abstract and symbolic, and more like some kind of fantastical world-building. So I yanked that back out.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/no-shirt/no-shirt-detail-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Here's one of the hikers, enjoying a view. It was fun for me to figure out just the right amount of detail to include, so the illustration felt sufficiently 'alive'—without going too far and changing the vibe of the design. I felt like the birds were a good call, but much beyond that may have been overkill.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/no-shirt/no-shirt-detail-2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Here's the other traveler. I wanted to include a fair bit of detail, but made my concession to details lost at small sizes by darkening the figures quite a bit—they mostly appear as silhouettes, after all.&lt;/p&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;I wanted to include some pots and pans—that's what's hanging off his pack here—because the story described their clanking a couple times.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/no-shirt/no-shirt-detail-3.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;I was really happy with how the shading on the underside of these curled fingers turned out.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/no-shirt/no-shirt-jacket.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;Here's how the book might look in print. It's pretty narrow, so I erred on the side of safety and left the spine blank, apart from that bit of ribbon at the bottom. The author plans to self-publish using CreateSpace.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/no-shirt/no-shirt-back.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;…and here's the back cover. I kept it pretty simple, even though there's not a lot of copy back there—because I didn't want to compete with the front cover image.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/no-shirt/interior-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;
		&lt;p&gt;I laid out the interior as well, here's a page from it. I used a pair of thumbs to divide sections, to call back to the pair of hitchhiking friends.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;about-the-book&quot;&gt;About the Book&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought it was a fun and quick read—I had a blast with the project, and I wish Steve every success!&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 30 Sep 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2013/09/30/no-shirt-no-shoes-no-service.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2013/09/30/no-shirt-no-shoes-no-service.html</guid>
        
        <category>illustration</category>
        
        <category>print layout</category>
        
        <category>cover design</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Eve of Light</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I lucked into the design for a series of sci-fi novels by Harambee K Grey-Sun. The first of the series, Bloodlight (technically a prequel to the series proper) came my way late last year—and we’ve been building the covers for the subsequent stories ever since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are a real treat for me, because they’re fun to read—and I have a chance to flex quite a bit creatively. Harambee is basically a dream client.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;bloodlight&quot;&gt;Bloodlight&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/eve-of-light/bloodlight-cover.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;The ebook cover for the prequel / origin story: Bloodlight.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/eve-of-light/corona.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Harambee asked specifically for a corona to sit over the eye on the cover—this is relevant to the story. I used flat, concentric rings to convey the idea while keeping the overall look pretty stark. I also used some mottled colors all across the skin here, in order to key to a few racial themes within the book.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried to keep the cover predominantly bright, and with brilliant colors (mostly sticking to magenta and cyan), because the book also deals uniquely with light.&lt;/p&gt;
	&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/eve-of-light/bloodlight-jacket.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;We only set Bloodlight up for ebook, but here's how it might look in print.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;broken-angels&quot;&gt;Broken Angels&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/eve-of-light/broken-angels-cover.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Here's the second book Harambee and I worked together on — the first story in the series proper. I kept it stylistically similar to Bloodlight, but not totally identical.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/eve-of-light/oroborous.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;The oroborous is a pertinant symbol in the book, devouring itself endlessly. It also keys to themes of new (though not always wonderful) beginnings.
&lt;p&gt;I kept the same bright color palette I used for the Bloodlight cover, because light is used within the book in a similar way—but the look is very slightly grimier and darker.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/eve-of-light/broken-angels-jacket.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;This one was set up for both print and ebook—the print version was published using Createspace. Here's a view of the cover and spine…&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/eve-of-light/broken-angels-back.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;…and here's a view of the back cover and spine. The yellow bands are meant to introduce a slightly glitchy element to the look of the book—we'd like each book to look a little more dark and 'off' than the last.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/eve-of-light/interior-1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;Here's the layout for the book's interior. It's meant to be transparent, placing the story first—but there are a few style elements pulled in from the cover. The typeface fot the chapter head (Interstate) for instance. And the infinity symbol is a visual nod to the oroborous, and fits the same themes that illustration does.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;divinities-entangled&quot;&gt;Divinities, Entangled&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/eve-of-light/divinities-cover.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;And here's the third book (second in the proper series)—Divinities, Entangled.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/eve-of-light/grapes.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;p&gt;Harambee suggested the grapes-as-skulls visual—I did explore some &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.behance.net/wip/182789/428059&quot;&gt;other concepts&lt;/a&gt;, but ultimately rolled back to his initial suggestion, which was a strong one. This visual makes a lot of sense toward the end of the book.&lt;/p&gt;
 
&lt;p&gt;Here we pull further away from the very bright colors of the first couple covers, toward more tertiary (and warmer) ones.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/eve-of-light/divinities-jacket.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;And here it is with the spine. The black band helps the title stand out more, and helps break up the repetition in the skulls. We also used a grey background here, rather than white—we'd like to slowly work our way toward solid black by the series' end.&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Whether he’s doing my covers or my interiors, Phillip Gessert never disappoints. In fact, he usually surprises—in a good way. His cover for my book BloodLight took my original idea and punted it into another dimension. I’ve lost count of the number of compliments I’ve received on it—even people who didn’t like the book rave about the cover!&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;He’s just as good with interiors.  How many other designers out there take time to read a book from beginning to end—prose or poetry—then try to find just the right font to match the content and theme?&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Incredibly creative in his own right, Phillip is always receptive to the writer’s ideas and gives them the last word—he’s in no way overbearing. Just an overall fantastic designer for writers who want their books to make an impact from first sight to last page.&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Harambee K. Grey-Sun&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
	&lt;img src=&quot;/img/portfolio/eve-of-light/jackets-array.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;
	&lt;figcaption&gt;&lt;/figcaption&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-author&quot;&gt;The Author&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find out more about Harambee at his website, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.nextpoet.net&quot;&gt;nextpoet.net&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2013 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2013/09/04/eve-of-light.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2013/09/04/eve-of-light.html</guid>
        
        <category>branding</category>
        
        <category>print layout</category>
        
        <category>cover design</category>
        
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
